Guide to the Jerome New Frank Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- WRITINGS, SPEECHES & PANEL DISCUSSIONS, 1927-1957; Series VI; 21' (50 boxes)
  - Proposed Books
    - Biography of Julius Rosenwald
      - Research notes compiled by Stanley Rayfield, undated (Box 148, Folder 354-356)
      - Research notes compiled by Stanley Rayfield, undated (Box 149, Folder 357-360)
      - Preliminary drafts by Stanley Rayfield, undated (Box 149, Folder 361)
      - Research notes compiled by Florence Kiper Frank, undated (Box 149, Folder 362)
      - Preliminary drafts by Florence Kiper Frank, undated (Box 149, Folder 363-364)
      - Preliminary drafts by Florence Kiper Frank, undated (Box 150, Folder 365)
      - Research notes compiled by JNF, undated (Box 150, Folder 366-369)
      - Preliminary drafts by JNF, undated (Box 150, Folder 370)
      - Preliminary drafts by JNF, undated (Box 151, Folder 371-374)
      - Publishing agreements, 1932, 1936 (Box 151, Folder 375)
      - Printed research material, 1924-1932, 1934-1936, 1938, undated (Box 151, Folder 376)
      - Printed research material, 1924-1932, 1934-1936, 1938, undated (Box 152, Folder 377)
    - Biography of Charles Evans Hughes
      - Preface (originally written for Julius Rosenwald biography), undated (Box 152, Folder 378)
      - Chapter I, 18 Jul, 1944 (Box 152, Folder 379)
      - Chapter II, 1944 (Box 152, Folder 380)
      - "Hughes Naive View of 'Facts'", undated (Box 152, Folder 381)
      - Research Material
        - Miscellaneous pages (Box 152, Folder 382)
        - On Franklin D. Roosevelt's proposed judicial reforms (Box 152, Folder 383)
        - On Hughes and Theodore Roosevelt (Box 152, Folder 384)
        - On Hughes as a judge (Box 152, Folder 385)
        - On Hughes as a statesman (Box 152, Folder 386)
        - On Hughes' background (Box 152, Folder 387)
        - On Hughes' beliefs about conservation and foreign trade (Box 152, Folder 388)
        - On Hughes' economic beliefs (Box 152, Folder 389)
        - On the cult of the robe (Box 152, Folder 390)
        - Printed material, 1931, 1937, 1940, 1942, 1944 (Box 153, Folder 391)
    - Biography of Theodore Roosevelt
      - Outlines
        - "Free Enterprise and Conservation," 18 Sep, 1944 (Box 153, Folder 392)
        - "T. R.," 25 May, 1945 (Box 153, Folder 393)
        - "Reasons for a New Life of Theodore Roosevelt," 12 Jun, 1945 (Box 153, Folder 394)
        - "Reasons for a New Life of Theodore Roosevelt," 15 Jun, 1945 (Box 153, Folder 395)
        - "Reasons for a New Life of Theodore Roosevelt," 19 Jun, 1945 (Box 153, Folder 396)
        - "Revisiting Theodore Roosevelt," 29 Jun, 1945 (Box 153, Folder 397)
        - "Revisiting Theodore Roosevelt, 30 Jun, 1945 (Box 153, Folder 398)
        - Untitled, 22-23 Oct, 1945 (Box 153, Folder 399)
        - "Reasons for a New Life of Theodore Roosevelt", undated (Box 153, Folder 400)
        - Miscellaneous pages (Box 153, Folder 401)
      - Research Material
        - Biographical data (Box 153, Folder 402)
        - General historical data (Box 153, Folder 403)
        - On economics and comparison with FDR (Box 153, Folder 404)
        - On economics and comparison with FDR (Box 154, Folder 405)
        - Printed material, 1942, 1944-1945 (Box 154, Folder 406)
        - Printed material: "The Morgenthau Diaries", 1947 (Box 154, Folder 407)
  - Articles
    - "The Strange Case of Obadiah Pitch", 1927 (Box 154, Folder 408)
    - "Are Judges Human?", [1931?] (Box 154, Folder 409)
    - "Cardozo and the Value of Myths", 1931 (Box 154, Folder 410)
    - "Freud and the Law", [1931?] (Box 154, Folder 411)
    - "Mr. Justice Holmes and Non-Euclidean Legal Thinking" [1 of 2 folders], 1932 (Box 154, Folder 412)
    - "Mr. Justice Holmes and Non-Euclidean Legal Thinking" [2 of 2 folders], 1932 (Box 154, Folder 413)
    - "What Courts Do in Fact", 1932 (Box 154, Folder 414)
    - "What Judges Often Forget", 1932 (Box 155, Folder 415)
    - "Lawlessness", 1933 (Box 155, Folder 416)
    - "Why Not a Clinical Lawyer-School?", 1933 (Box 155, Folder 417)
    - Introduction to Studies in Federal Taxation by Randolph E. Paul, 1937 (Box 155, Folder 418)
    - "Red White and Blue Herrings", [1938?] (Box 155, Folder 419)
    - "A Government of Laws and Not of Men", [1939?] (Box 155, Folder 420)
    - Letter to the Editor, The Nation, 1939 (Box 155, Folder 421)
    - "Bondage to Bonds or Doubts about Debt", 1940 (Box 155, Folder 422)
    - "Government Financing of War", 1940 (Box 155, Folder 423)
    - "Integration and Utility Investors", 1940 (Box 155, Folder 424)
    - "Is There Need for Government Regulation of Business?", 1940 (Box 155, Folder 425)
    - "Lest We Forget: Lessons for the SEC and the Utility Industry To Be Gleaned from the Financial History of Railroads" [1 of 3 folders], 1940 (Box 155, Folder 426)
    - "Lest We Forget: Lessons for the SEC and the Utility Industry To Be Gleaned from the Financial History of Railroads" [2 of 3 folders], 1940 (Box 155, Folder 427)
    - "Lest We Forget: Lessons for the SEC and the Utility Industry To Be Gleaned from the Financial History of Railroads" [3 of 3 folders], 1940 (Box 155, Folder 428)
    - "The SEC and Disciplinary Proceedings", 1940 (Box 155, Folder 429)
    - Untitled article prepared for Electrical World, 1940 (Box 155, Folder 430)
    - "Confessions of an Ex-Isolationist" [1 of 2 folders], [1941?] (Box 156, Folder 431)
    - "Confessions of an Ex-Isolationist" [2 of 2 folders], [1941?] (Box 156, Folder 432)
    - "Epithetical Jurisprudence and the Work of the Securities and Exchange Commission in the Administration of Chapter X of the Bankruptcy Act", 1941 (Box 156, Folder 433)
    - On preparing for peace in time of war, 1941 (Box 156, Folder 434)
    - "A Red-White-and-Blue Herring", 1941 (Box 156, Folder 435)
    - "A Red-White-and-Blue Herring": reviews and critical response, 1941 (Box 156, Folder 436)
    - The High Cost of Woman's Economic Independence--The Case of Apostle v. Pappas, 1942 (Box 156, Folder 437)
    - "Court-House Government" (or: "It Might Happen to You"), 1942 (Box 156, Folder 438)
    - "Criticism of Judges and Freedom of the Press. Bridges v. California", 1942 (Box 156, Folder 439)
    - "Dangerous Politeness", 1942 (Box 156, Folder 440)
    - "Ghost-Writing", 1942 (Box 156, Folder 441)
    - Auto Accidents--An Old Problem Will Soon Again Confront Us, 1942 (Box 156, Folder 442)
    - "New York's Twilight?", 1942 (Box 156, Folder 443)
    - "Play Boy", 1942 (Box 156, Folder 444)
    - "Pressure Groups and Democracy", 1942 (Box 156, Folder 445)
    - "Prestige: Its Vices and Virtues", 1942 (Box 156, Folder 446)
    - "Soft-Boiled Patriotism", 1942 (Box 156, Folder 447)
    - "Uncle Sam and the Future of Our Cities", 1942 (Box 157, Folder 448)
    - "The War and the Patent System", 1942 (Box 157, Folder 449)
    - "War Profits. U.S. v. Bethlehem Steel Corporation", 1942 (Box 157, Folder 450)
    - "What's Wrong With Our Patent System?" [1 of 2 folders], 1942 (Box 157, Folder 451)
    - "What's Wrong With Our Patent System?" [2 of 2 folders], 1942 (Box 157, Folder 452)
    - Everybody's Business", 1943 (Box 157, Folder 453)
    - Proposed columns for United Feature Syndicate, 1943 (Box 157, Folder 454)
    - "Regionalism" or "The Menace of Boatism" or "The New Isolationism", 1943 (Box 157, Folder 455)
    - "The Spark-Plug of Democracy", 1943 (Box 157, Folder 456)
    - "The Speech of Judges: A Dissenting Opinion", 1943 (Box 157, Folder 457)
    - "White-Collar Justice", 1943 (Box 157, Folder 458)
    - "You Feel as You Act", 1943 (Box 157, Folder 459)
    - "Conservation and Wasteful Foreign Trade", 1944 (Box 157, Folder 460)
    - "Fashions and Democracy", 1944 (Box 157, Folder 461)
    - "Free Enterprise and Conservation", 1944 (Box 157, Folder 462)
    - "Incompetent Youth", 1944 (Box 157, Folder 463)
    - "Overhauling the Cabinet" [1 of 2 folders], 1944 (Box 157, Folder 464)
    - "Overhauling the Cabinet" [2 of 2 folders], 1944 (Box 158, Folder 465)
    - "Small Business", 1944 (Box 158, Folder 466)
    - "An Unsettled Conflict", 1944 (Box 158, Folder 467)
    - "What Does History Teach?" (or: "Deadly Parallels"), 1944 (Box 158, Folder 468)
    - "Women Lawyers", 1944 (Box 158, Folder 469)
    - War Crimes: Punishment for Today--Precedent for Tomorrow, 1945 (Box 158, Folder 470)
    - "Ben Cohen" [1 of 2 folders], 1945 (Box 158, Folder 471)
    - "Ben Cohen" [2 of 2 folders], 1945 (Box 158, Folder 472)
    - "The Cult of the Robe", 1945 (Box 158, Folder 473)
    - "The First New Deal Judge: 1789-1798", 1945 (Box 158, Folder 474)
    - "The First Time in History", [1945?] (Box 158, Folder 475)
    - "The Great Words", 1945 (Box 158, Folder 476)
    - "How Big Is Big?" (or: "How Brandeis Split the Liberals"), 1945 (Box 158, Folder 477)
    - "'Jim' Forrestal Looks at Government", 1945 (Box 158, Folder 478)
    - "The New Sin", 1945 (Box 158, Folder 479)
    - Modern and Ancient Legal Pragmatism--John Dewey & Co. vs. Aristotle [1 of 6 folders], 1945 (Box 159, Folder 480)
    - "World Prosecutor", 1945 (Box 159, Folder 481)
    - "White-Collar Justice", 1946 (Box 159, Folder 482)
    - "A Plea for Lawyer-Schools", 1947 (Box 159, Folder 483)
    - "Self-Guardianship and Democracy:, 1947 (Box 159, Folder 484)
    - "A Sketch of an Influence", 1947 (Box 159, Folder 485)
    - "Words and Music: Some Remarks on Statutory Interpretation", 1947 (Box 159, Folder 486)
    - "The Making of the Roosevelt Myth", 1948 (Box 159, Folder 487)
    - "An Old Fogey Reacts: Some Comments on Democratic Values in Trial Courts and in Legal Education", 1948 (Box 159, Folder 488)
    - "Punishing Disease", 1948 (Box 159, Folder 489)
    - "Say It With Music" [1 of 2 folders], 1948 (Box 159, Folder 490)
    - "Say It With Music" [2 of 2 folders], 1948 (Box 159, Folder 491)
    - "Was Bryan Right?" (or: "Russia and Gold"), 1948 (Box 159, Folder 492)
    - "The Case for the Special Verdict", 1949 (Box 159, Folder 493)
    - "Legal Thinking in Three Dimensions", 1949 (Box 159, Folder 494)
    - "The Place of the Expert in a Democratic Society", 1949 (Box 160, Folder 495)
    - "It May Be You" [1 of 2 folders], 1950 (Box 160, Folder 496)
    - "It May Be You" [2 of 2 folders], 1950 (Box 160, Folder 497)
    - Modern and Ancient Legal Pragmatism--John Dewey & Co. vs. Aristotle [2 of 6 folders], 1950 (Box 160, Folder 498)
    - Modern and Ancient Legal Pragmatism--John Dewey & Co. vs. Aristotle [3 of 6 folders], 1950 (Box 160, Folder 499)
    - Modern and Ancient Legal Pragmatism--John Dewey & Co. vs. Aristotle [4 of 6 folders], 1950 (Box 160, Folder 500)
    - Modern and Ancient Legal Pragmatism--John Dewey & Co. vs. Aristotle [5 of 6 folders], 1950 (Box 161, Folder 501)
    - Modern and Ancient Legal Pragmatism--John Dewey & Co. vs. Aristotle [6 of 6 folders], 1950 (Box 161, Folder 502)
    - Civil Law Influences on the Common Law--Some Reflections on 'Comparative' and 'Contrastive' Law [1 of 4 folders], 1950 (Box 161, Folder 503)
    - "Something's Wrong with Our Jury System", 1950 (Box 161, Folder 504)
    - "Both Ends Against the Middle", 1951 (Box 161, Folder 505)
    - "The FBI and the Third Degree", 1951 (Box 161, Folder 506)
    - "Memorable Victories in the Fight for Justice", 1951 (Box 161, Folder 507)
    - "'Short of Sickness and Death': A Study of Moral Responsibility in Legal Criticism" [1 of 6 folders], 1951 (Box 161, Folder 508)
    - "'Short of Sickness and Death': A study of Moral Responsibility in Legal Criticism" [2 of 6 folders], 1951 (Box 162, Folder 509)
    - "'Short of Sickness and Death': A Study of Moral Responsibility in Legal Criticism" [3 of 6 folders], 1951 (Box 162, Folder 510)
    - "'Short of Sickness and Death': A Study of Moral Responsibility in Legal Criticism" [4 of 6 folders], 1951 (Box 162, Folder 511)
    - "'Short of Sickness and Death': A Study of Moral Responsibility in Legal Criticism" [5 of 6 folders], 1951 (Box 162, Folder 512)
    - ""Short of Sickness and Death': A Study of Moral Responsibility in Legal Criticism" [6 of 6 folders], 1951 (Box 162, Folder 513)
    - "Judicial Fact-Finding and Psychology", 1953 (Box 162, Folder 514)
    - "No Man Is Safe", 1953 (Box 162, Folder 515)
    - "Re Children's Court", 1953 (Box 163, Folder 516)
    - "Some Tame Reflections on Some Wild Facts", 1953 (Box 163, Folder 517)
    - "Comments on Sumner, The Full Faith and Credit Clause", 1954 (Box 163, Folder 518)
    - "A Conflict with Oblivion: Some Observations on the Founders of Legal Pragmatism", 1954 (Box 163, Folder 519)
    - "The Lawyer's Role in Modern Society: A Round Table", 1955 (Box 163, Folder 520)
    - Civil Law Influences on the Common Law--Some Reflections on 'Comparative' and 'Contrastive' Law [2 of 4 folders], 1956 (Box 163, Folder 521)
    - Civil Law Influences on the Common Law--Some Reflections on 'Comparative' and 'Contrastive' Law [3 of 4 folders], 1956 (Box 163, Folder 522)
    - Civil Law Influences on the Common Law--Some Reflections on 'Comparative' and 'Contrastive' Law [4 of 4 folders], 1956 (Box 163, Folder 523)
    - The Citizen and His Law--In Twenty Minutes, 1956 (Box 164, Folder 524)
    - "Some Reflections on Judge Learned Hand", 1957 (Box 164, Folder 525)
    - "The Art of Mental Self-Defense", undated (Box 164, Folder 526)
    - "Comedy", undated (Box 164, Folder 527)
    - "A Comment on Professor Maguire's Paper on 'Criminal Evidence", undated (Box 164, Folder 528)
    - "Comments on the Curriculum and Teaching Methods of a University Law School", undated (Box 164, Folder 529)
    - "Constructive Wishful Thinking", undated (Box 164, Folder 530)
    - "Experiments in the Prevention of Perjury", undated (Box 164, Folder 531)
    - "Fascism and Communism", undated (Box 164, Folder 532)
    - "God-Makers of the Western World", undated (Box 164, Folder 533)
    - "The Great Words", undated (Box 164, Folder 534)
    - "How to Do Business with Your Government", undated (Box 164, Folder 535)
    - "It Could Happen to You," co-authored with Barbara Frank Kristein, undated (Box 164, Folder 536)
    - "Judicial Ignorance", undated (Box 164, Folder 537)
    - "Language in Action", undated (Box 164, Folder 538)
    - "Legal Theology" (or: "Precedents and the Higher Criticism"), undated (Box 164, Folder 539)
    - "The Moral Irresponsibility of Felix Cohen", undated (Box 164, Folder 540)
    - On bias and race discrimination in colleges and universities, undated (Box 164, Folder 541)
    - On Constitutional interpretation, undated (Box 164, Folder 542)
    - On law and psychology, undated (Box 164, Folder 543)
    - On psychiatry and administrative officials, undated (Box 164, Folder 544)
    - On Roscoe Pound, undated (Box 164, Folder 545)
    - On stare decisis, undated (Box 164, Folder 546)
    - On the third degree, undated (Box 164, Folder 547)
    - "Peace", undated (Box 164, Folder 548)
    - "The Prosecutor and the Tricks of the Trade", undated (Box 164, Folder 549)
    - "Punishment Without Crime: Our Modern Debtor's Prisons," co-authored with Barbara Frank Kristein, undated (Box 164, Folder 550)
    - "Re Mores", undated (Box 164, Folder 551)
    - "The Relative Certainty of Constitutional Law", undated (Box 164, Folder 552)
    - Shoot stories, untitled, undated (Box 165, Folder 553)
    - "Spending Program", undated (Box 165, Folder 554)
    - "The Supreme Court's New Constitutional Approach", undated (Box 165, Folder 555)
    - "They Didn't Shoot Lincoln", undated (Box 165, Folder 556)
    - "Too Much Unity" (or: "The Value of Pressure Groups"), undated (Box 165, Folder 557)
    - "What Lawyers Do", undated (Box 165, Folder 558)
    - "The Upper Court Myth," co-authored with Barbara Frank Kristein, undated (Box 165, Folder 559)
  - Book Reviews
    - The Bramble Bush: Some Lectures on Law and Its Study by Karl N. Llewellyn, 1931 (Box 165, Folder 560)
    - The Modern Corporation and Private Property by Adolph A. Berle and Gardiner C. Means, 1933 (Box 165, Folder 561)
    - The Structure of the American Economy by Gardiner C. Means, 1939 (Box 165, Folder 562)
    - Outline of Lectures on Jurisprudence by Roscoe Pound, 1943 (Box 165, Folder 563)
    - Democracy in America by Alexis de Tocqueville, 1945 (Box 165, Folder 564)
    - Practical Applications of Democracyby Huszar, 1946 (Box 165, Folder 565)
    - Letter to the Editor, New York Times Book Reviewin reply to Edward S. Corwin, author of Total War and the Constitution, 1947 (Box 165, Folder 566)
    - "Cardozo and the Upper-Court Myth," Selected Writings of Benjamin N. Cardozo by Margaret E. Hall, 1948 (Box 165, Folder 567)
    - Men of Law by William Seagle, 1948 (Box 165, Folder 568)
    - Scientific Man vs. Power Politics by Hans J. Morgenthau, 1948 (Box 165, Folder 569)
    - The Vital Center by Arthur Schlesinger, Jr., 1949 (Box 165, Folder 570)
    - Authority and the Individual by Bertrand Russell, 1950 (Box 165, Folder 571)
    - Legal Philosophy from Plato to Hegel by Huntington Cairns, 1950 (Box 165, Folder 572)
    - New Paths of Law by Roscoe Pound, 1950 (Box 165, Folder 573)
    - Rediscovery of Justice by F. R. Bienenfeld, 1950 (Box 166, Folder 574)
    - Law: The Science of Inefficiency by William Seagle, 1953 (Box 166, Folder 575)
    - Judicial Legislationby Cahill, undated (Box 166, Folder 576)
  - Speeches
    - Address at Hessian Hills School, 1931 (Box 166, Folder 577)
    - New School for Social Research--First Talk, [1931?] (Box 166, Folder 578)
    - "Freud and the Law", 1931 (Box 166, Folder 579)
    - New School for Social Research--Second Talk, [1931?] (Box 166, Folder 580)
    - New School for Social Research Talks--research material, [1931?] (Box 166, Folder 581)
    - Langdell Lecture--Harvard Law School, [1931?] (Box 166, Folder 582)
    - "Re Mores", 1931 (Box 166, Folder 583)
    - "Law and Magic", 1932 (Box 166, Folder 584)
    - "Litigation" [1 of 2 folders], 1932 (Box 166, Folder 585)
    - "Litigation" [2 of 2 folders], 1932 (Box 166, Folder 586)
    - "Experimental Jurisprudence and the New Deal", 1933 (Box 166, Folder 587)
    - "Farmers as Consumers", 1933 (Box 166, Folder 588)
    - "120,000,000 of Us are Consumers", 1933 (Box 166, Folder 589)
    - "Realistic Reflections on 'Law' as a Constructive Social Force", 1933 (Box 166, Folder 590)
    - "Trends in National Recovery", 1933 (Box 166, Folder 591)
    - "What Constitutes a Good Legal Education", 1933 (Box 166, Folder 592)
    - Address before the Federal Employees Union at the National Museum, 1934 (Box 166, Folder 593)
    - "Dairy Marketing Agreements and Licenses", 1934 (Box 166, Folder 594)
    - "Education and the New Deal", 1934 (Box 166, Folder 595)
    - "Jefferson and the Spirit of the New Deal", 1934 (Box 166, Folder 596)
    - "The New Deal and the Deregimentation of the Dispossessed", 1934 (Box 167, Folder 597)
    - Untitled outline for an address, 1934 (Box 167, Folder 598)
    - "Facing the Facts", 1935 (Box 167, Folder 599)
    - Index to addresses, 1933-1935 (Box 167, Folder 600)
    - New School for Social Research--Second Talk, 1937 (Box 167, Folder 601)
    - Address before the Harvard Business Club, 1938 (Box 167, Folder 602)
    - Address before the Law School Alumni, University of Buffalo, 1938 (Box 167, Folder 603)
    - Address before the National Press Club, 1938 (Box 167, Folder 604)
    - Address before the Washington Hebrew Association, 1938 (Box 167, Folder 605)
    - "Administrative Flexibility or Industrial Paralysis?", 1938 (Box 167, Folder 606)
    - "Corporate Reorganizations and the Chandler Act", 1938 (Box 167, Folder 607)
    - "A New World", 1938 (Box 167, Folder 608)
    - "Nineteenth Century Pump Priming", 1938 (Box 167, Folder 609)
    - "Too Much Interest in Interest", 1938 (Box 167, Folder 610)
    - "What's Wrong with the Law Schools", 1938 (Box 167, Folder 611)
    - "Why We Should Save America First", 1938 (Box 167, Folder 612)
    - "Accounting for Investors: The Fundamental Importance of Corporate Earning Power", 1939 (Box 167, Folder 613)
    - Address before the Association of Customers' Brokers, 1939 (Box 167, Folder 614)
    - Address before the Business Advisory Council, Washington, D. C., 1939 (Box 167, Folder 615)
    - Address before the New York Financial Writers' Association, 1939 (Box 167, Folder 616)
    - "Advance Administrative Decisions", 1939 (Box 167, Folder 617)
    - "One-Eyed Elephants and Mono-Comps", 1939 (Box 168, Folder 618)
    - "EC and the Rubber Hose" [1 of 3 folders], 1939 (Box 168, Folder 619)
    - "SEC and the Rubber Hose" [2 of 3 folders], 1939 (Box 168, Folder 620)
    - "SEC and the Rubber Hose" [3 of 3 folders], 1939 (Box 168, Folder 621)
    - "Corporation Management and the SEC", 1940 (Box 168, Folder 622)
    - "Fairness and Feasibility", 1940 (Box 168, Folder 623)
    - "In Time of War Prepare for Peace", 1940 (Box 168, Folder 624)
    - "Regional Financing", 1940 (Box 168, Folder 625)
    - "The Sin of Perfectionism" [1 of 2 folders], 1940 (Box 169, Folder 626)
    - "The Sin of Perfectionism" [2 of 2 folders], 1940 (Box 169, Folder 627)
    - "Yodellers and Rodellers", 1941 (Box 169, Folder 628)
    - "The Facts in the Case", 1942 (Box 169, Folder 629)
    - "The Twentieth Century Phase of the American Revolution", 1942 (Box 169, Folder 630)
    - "What Is Latent in a Patent", 1942 (Box 169, Folder 631)
    - Address at U. S. Army Camp, Orangeburg, New York, 1943 (Box 169, Folder 632)
    - Address before the Friends of Democracy, Inc., 1944 (Box 169, Folder 633)
    - "The Operations of Federal Administrative Agencies", 1944 (Box 169, Folder 634)
    - "The Place of the Expert in a Democratic Society", 1944 (Box 169, Folder 635)
    - Remarks at dinner in honor of Senator Wagner, 1944 (Box 169, Folder 636)
    - "Women Lawyers", 1944 (Box 169, Folder 637)
    - Address before the Legal Aid Society at Downtown Association, 1945 (Box 169, Folder 638)
    - "The New Sin", 1945 (Box 169, Folder 639)
    - "Science in the National Economy", 1945 (Box 169, Folder 640)
    - Address before a women's club, 1946 (Box 169, Folder 641)
    - Introduction of Judge John Knox, 1946 (Box 169, Folder 642)
    - "Judging the Judges", 1946 (Box 169, Folder 643)
    - "The Menace of the New Technocracy", 1946 (Box 169, Folder 644)
    - "The Most Dangerous Specialist: The Specialist in Imperialism", 1946 (Box 169, Folder 645)
    - New School for Social Research--Third Talk, [1946?] (Box 169, Folder 646)
    - Brooklyn Institute--First Talk, 1946 (Box 170, Folder 647)
    - "The Specialists and the General-ists", 1946 (Box 170, Folder 648)
    - Address before the War Veterans' Bar Association, 1947 (Box 170, Folder 649)
    - Address on I Am an American Day, 1947 (Box 170, Folder 650)
    - "Concerning Some Unphilosophic Philosophizing", 1947 (Box 170, Folder 651)
    - "Words and Music", 1947 (Box 170, Folder 652)
    - Address at banquet in honor of Judge Sylvester Ryan, 1948 (Box 170, Folder 653)
    - Princeton University Talks., 1948 (Box 170, Folder 654)
      See: box 142, folder 285
    - Remarks at Golden Quill Dinner in honor of Judge Simon Rifkind, 1948 (Box 170, Folder 655)
    - Remarks at presentation to Dr. Harry Stack Sullivan of the William Alanson White Memorial Award, 1948 (Box 170, Folder 656)
    - "Social Sciences and the World Today" [1 of 3 folders], 1948 (Box 170, Folder 657)
    - "Social Sciences and the World Today" [2 of 3 folders], 1948 (Box 170, Folder 658)
    - "Social Sciences and the World Today" [3 of 3 folders], 1948 (Box 170, Folder 659)
    - Brooklyn Institute--Second Talks, 1949 (Box 171, Folder 660)
    - Brooklyn Institute--Third Talk [1 of 2 folders], 1949 (Box 171, Folder 661)
    - Brooklyn Institute--Third Talk [2 of 2 folders], 1949 (Box 171, Folder 662)